<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<style>

<?xml-stylesheet href="/includes/blog-feed/atom.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Paoletti Law Blog</title>
    <description>At Paoletti &amp;amp; Gusmano, Attorneys at Law, our Bridgeport attorneys have criminal defense experience.
</description>
    <link>http://www.paolettilaw.net//</link>
    <atom:link href="http://www.paolettilaw.net//feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2014 20:42:07 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2014 20:42:07 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.4.0</generator>
    
      <entry>
        <title>2 arrested on drug charges after traffic stop</title>
        <description>Any time someone is charged with a drug crime, the possible penalties are severe, and it is crucial to treat the situation seriously. Defendants may have several different defense options depending on whether the charge was for possession or possession with intent to sell and whether or not it was a first offense. The first step to defending against a drug charge is to be fully informed on how Connecticut law applies to the individual's situation.</description>
        <published>Fri, 03 Oct 2014 00:00:00 -0400</published>
        <link>http://www.paolettilaw.net//drug%20charges/2014/10/03/2-arrested-on-drug-charges-after-traffic-stop.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.paolettilaw.net//drug%20charges/2014/10/03/2-arrested-on-drug-charges-after-traffic-stop.html</guid>
        
        <category>drug charges</category>
        
      </entry>
    
      <entry>
        <title>Violent crimes: What is a mandatory minimum sentence?</title>
        <description>While an acquittal or dismissal of charges is always the best case scenario in a criminal defense case, it's also smart to consider what can happen in the case of a conviction. The need for a defense attorney doesn't stop once the jury hands down their decision; experienced representation can still be helpful during the sentencing phase of any criminal conviction.</description>
        <published>Thu, 25 Sep 2014 00:00:00 -0400</published>
        <link>http://www.paolettilaw.net//violent%20crimes/2014/09/25/violent-crimes-what-is-a-mandatory-minimum-sentence.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.paolettilaw.net//violent%20crimes/2014/09/25/violent-crimes-what-is-a-mandatory-minimum-sentence.html</guid>
        
        <category>violent crimes</category>
        
      </entry>
    
      <entry>
        <title>Criminal charges: The importance of the pretrial conference</title>
        <description>When you find out you are being charged with a crime, it is normal to immediately begin thinking about what will happen at the trial and what the eventual outcome will be. It is important, however, to take each step in the criminal court process as it comes, and try to stay focused on the task at hand instead of what will happen later on.</description>
        <published>Fri, 19 Sep 2014 00:00:00 -0400</published>
        <link>http://www.paolettilaw.net//criminal%20defense/2014/09/19/criminal-charges-the-importance-of-the-pretrial-conference.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.paolettilaw.net//criminal%20defense/2014/09/19/criminal-charges-the-importance-of-the-pretrial-conference.html</guid>
        
        <category>criminal defense</category>
        
      </entry>
    
      <entry>
        <title>Drug charges: What you need to know</title>
        <description>Many states are prosecuting drug crimes with increasing aggressiveness, and Connecticut is no different. Depending on the amount of the substance and the substance itself, drug convictions can come with serious penalties, including significant prison time. Understanding what your charges mean and the possible penalties is crucial to understanding your criminal defense options</description>
        <published>Fri, 12 Sep 2014 00:00:00 -0400</published>
        <link>http://www.paolettilaw.net//drug%20charges/2014/09/12/drug-charges-what-you-need-to-know.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.paolettilaw.net//drug%20charges/2014/09/12/drug-charges-what-you-need-to-know.html</guid>
        
        <category>drug charges</category>
        
      </entry>
    
      <entry>
        <title>Drunk driving: Possible penalties</title>
        <description>Connecticut takes driving under the influence seriously, and that can mean serious penalties for those convicted. In this state, drivers are considered over the legal limit if they are over the age of 21 with a blood alcohol content of .08 or above or under 21 with a blood alcohol content of .02 or above. Knowing the possible consequences can help &lt;a href=&quot;/DUI-DWI/DUI-DWI.html&quot; &gt;drunk driving&lt;/a&gt; defendants get a better understanding of their cases and their options.</description>
        <published>Wed, 03 Sep 2014 00:00:00 -0400</published>
        <link>http://www.paolettilaw.net//drunk%20driving/2014/09/03/drunk-driving-possible-penalties.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.paolettilaw.net//drunk%20driving/2014/09/03/drunk-driving-possible-penalties.html</guid>
        
        <category>drunk driving</category>
        
      </entry>
    
      <entry>
        <title>Domestic violence: Does there have to be physical proof?</title>
        <description>While physical evidence such as photographs of bruising can certainly result in domestic violence charges, physical proof of an alleged altercation does not have to be present for an individual to be charged with domestic violence in Connecticut. If physical documentation does exist, however, it can have serious implications for the defendants.</description>
        <published>Fri, 29 Aug 2014 00:00:00 -0400</published>
        <link>http://www.paolettilaw.net//domestic%20violence/2014/08/29/domestic-violence-does-there-have-to-be-physical-proof.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.paolettilaw.net//domestic%20violence/2014/08/29/domestic-violence-does-there-have-to-be-physical-proof.html</guid>
        
        <category>domestic violence</category>
        
      </entry>
    
      <entry>
        <title>Murder conviction overturned, case could be headed back to trial</title>
        <description>A Connecticut man who had previously sentenced to 60 years in prison after being found guilty of murder has now succeeded in getting the conviction overturned and may be headed for a new trial. According to reports, the man was convicted of murder in 2011 after he was accused of fatally shooting another man outside of the Cardinal's Club on April 27, 2008.</description>
        <published>Fri, 22 Aug 2014 00:00:00 -0400</published>
        <link>http://www.paolettilaw.net//violent%20crimes/2014/08/22/murder-conviction-overturned-case-could-be-headed-back-to-trial.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.paolettilaw.net//violent%20crimes/2014/08/22/murder-conviction-overturned-case-could-be-headed-back-to-trial.html</guid>
        
        <category>violent crimes</category>
        
      </entry>
    
      <entry>
        <title>Connecticut police officer accused of stomping on suspect</title>
        <description>A police officer in Connecticut has been arrested and charged for allegedly stomping on a man's head after the man was already on the ground. The man had been shot with a taser before he was stomped on. The charges say that this alleged attack was a violation of that man's rights, and a video of the incident has now surfaced.</description>
        <published>Fri, 15 Aug 2014 00:00:00 -0400</published>
        <link>http://www.paolettilaw.net//criminal%20defense/2014/08/15/connecticut-police-officer-accused-of-stomping-on-suspect.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.paolettilaw.net//criminal%20defense/2014/08/15/connecticut-police-officer-accused-of-stomping-on-suspect.html</guid>
        
        <category>criminal defense</category>
        
      </entry>
    
      <entry>
        <title>Two arrested on drug charges at Connecticut motel</title>
        <description>Two Connecticut residents are facing drug charges after police arrested them at a motel in Manchester. According to reports, police had the Studio 6 Motel under surveillance when they were told that a man and prostitute were reportedly meeting in one of the hotel's rooms. Officers say they watched as the 44-year-old man knocked on the door of the room and threw what they later identified as heroin into a garbage can.</description>
        <published>Fri, 08 Aug 2014 00:00:00 -0400</published>
        <link>http://www.paolettilaw.net//drug%20charges/2014/08/08/two-arrested-on-drug-charges-at-connecticut-motel.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.paolettilaw.net//drug%20charges/2014/08/08/two-arrested-on-drug-charges-at-connecticut-motel.html</guid>
        
        <category>drug charges</category>
        
      </entry>
    
      <entry>
        <title>Man facing DUI after picking up son from police</title>
        <description>A Connecticut man has been charged with drunk driving after he allegedly exhibited signs of intoxication when he went to pick up his son. According to reports, the Oxford man's 15-year-old son had been detained at the Naugatuck State Forest by officers after he allegedly had been caught riding a motor scooter illegally. The teen's three friends were also detained, according to the Department of Energy and Environmental Protection.</description>
        <published>Fri, 01 Aug 2014 00:00:00 -0400</published>
        <link>http://www.paolettilaw.net//drunk%20driving/2014/08/01/man-facing-dui-after-picking-up-son-from-police.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.paolettilaw.net//drunk%20driving/2014/08/01/man-facing-dui-after-picking-up-son-from-police.html</guid>
        
        <category>drunk driving</category>
        
      </entry>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
