<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Your awesome title</title>
    <description>Write an awesome description for your new site here. You can edit this line in _config.yml. It will appear in your document head meta (for Google search results) and in your feed.xml site description.
</description>
    <link>http://www.paolettilaw.net//</link>
    <atom:link href="http://www.paolettilaw.net//feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2014 22:59:25 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2014 22:59:25 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.4.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Criminal charges: The importance of the pretrial conference</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;When you find out you are being charged with a crime, it is normal to immediately begin thinking about what will happen at the trial and what the eventual outcome will be. It is important, however, to take each step in the criminal court process as it comes, and try to stay focused on the task at hand instead of what will happen later on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many defendants may not know about the pretrial conference step or even understand what it is, but this is an important part of determining your &lt;a href=&quot;/Criminal-Defense/What-to-Do-if-You-Are-Arrested.shtml&quot;&gt;criminal defense&lt;/a&gt; strategy, and what is decided here can have a major impact on the case as whole. Basically, the pretrial conference happens after the arraignment if you decide to plead not guilty to the charge and the case proceeds to trial. During the pretrial conference, you will discuss the details of your case with your attorney, the possible outcomes and whether or not a plea bargain may be an option.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The pretrial conference is crucial and should be taken very seriously. It is important during this step to be as open and honest with your attorney as possible. The more information you can provide about the events surrounding the alleged incident the better. It is normal for defendants to be experiencing a wide range of emotions during this process, and talking out the details helps ensure your attorney has a clear and accurate understanding of your case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whether this is the first time you have been charged with a crime or you have been through the legal system before, having experienced legal representation that understands how Texas laws apply to your case is crucial to ensuring your rights are protected. Our webpage on &lt;a href=&quot;/Criminal-Defense/&quot;&gt;criminal defense&lt;/a&gt; has more information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Source:&lt;/b&gt; Paoletti &amp;amp; Gusmano, &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;/Criminal-Defense/The-Criminal-Defense-Process.shtml&quot;&gt;Connecticut Criminal Defense System&lt;/a&gt;&quot; Sep. 15, 2014&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2014 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.paolettilaw.net//criminal-defense/2014/09/19/criminal-charges-the-importance-of-the-pretrial-conference.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.paolettilaw.net//criminal-defense/2014/09/19/criminal-charges-the-importance-of-the-pretrial-conference.html</guid>
        
        <category>Criminal defense</category>
        
        <category>defense</category>
        
        
        <category>criminal-defense</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Drug charges: What you need to know</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;When you find out you are being charged with a crime, it is normal to immediately begin thinking about what will happen at the trial and what the eventual outcome will be. It is important, however, to take each step in the criminal court process as it comes, and try to stay focused on the task at hand instead of what will happen later on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many defendants may not know about the pretrial conference step or even understand what it is, but this is an important part of determining your &lt;a href=&quot;/Criminal-Defense/What-to-Do-if-You-Are-Arrested.shtml&quot;&gt;criminal defense&lt;/a&gt; strategy, and what is decided here can have a major impact on the case as whole. Basically, the pretrial conference happens after the arraignment if you decide to plead not guilty to the charge and the case proceeds to trial. During the pretrial conference, you will discuss the details of your case with your attorney, the possible outcomes and whether or not a plea bargain may be an option.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The pretrial conference is crucial and should be taken very seriously. It is important during this step to be as open and honest with your attorney as possible. The more information you can provide about the events surrounding the alleged incident the better. It is normal for defendants to be experiencing a wide range of emotions during this process, and talking out the details helps ensure your attorney has a clear and accurate understanding of your case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whether this is the first time you have been charged with a crime or you have been through the legal system before, having experienced legal representation that understands how Texas laws apply to your case is crucial to ensuring your rights are protected. Our webpage on &lt;a href=&quot;/Criminal-Defense/&quot;&gt;criminal defense&lt;/a&gt; has more information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Source:&lt;/b&gt; Paoletti &amp;amp; Gusmano, &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;/Criminal-Defense/The-Criminal-Defense-Process.shtml&quot;&gt;Connecticut Criminal Defense System&lt;/a&gt;&quot; Sep. 15, 2014&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2014 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.paolettilaw.net//drug-charges/2014/09/12/drug-charges-what-you-need-to-know.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.paolettilaw.net//drug-charges/2014/09/12/drug-charges-what-you-need-to-know.html</guid>
        
        <category>defense</category>
        
        <category>drug distribution</category>
        
        <category>drug offenses</category>
        
        <category>drug possession</category>
        
        <category>drug trafficking</category>
        
        <category>search and seizure</category>
        
        
        <category>drug-charges</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Drunk driving: Possible penalties</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Connecticut takes driving under the influence seriously, and that can mean serious penalties for those convicted. In this state, drivers are considered over the legal limit if they are over the age of 21 with a blood alcohol content of .08 or above or under 21 with a blood alcohol content of .02 or above. Knowing the possible consequences can help &lt;a href=&quot;/DUI-DWI/&quot;&gt;drunk driving&lt;/a&gt; defendants get a better understanding of their cases and their options.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Drivers in the state of Connecticut are considered to have given implied consent to be tested for alcohol while driving when they obtained their driver's licenses. This means drivers can immediately lose their licenses for six months if they refuse to take an alcohol analysis test, which can be a breath, urine or blood test.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If a driver is tested and the blood alcohol level is above the legal limit, the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dmv.org/ct-connecticut/automotive-law/dui.php&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;penalties&lt;/a&gt; depend on how high the blood-alcohol content was and whether it is the person's first offense. There are two types of penalties that those convicted of drunk driving may be subjected to: administrative and criminal. For those over the age of 21, a blood-alcohol content over .08 means no license for a minimum of 90 days, and if the blood-alcohol content is over .16, the license is suspended for 120 days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Criminal penalties are applied from the state court system instead of the Department of Motor Vehicles, and these criminal penalties are in addition to any administrative penalties already imposed. A first offense can result in a one-year license suspension. A second offense also suspends the license for one year, but the driver must also have an ignition interlock device for the two years after the suspension. Drivers who are convicted of a third DUI may lose their licenses permanently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Serious charges mean serious penalties, and serious penalties mean the need for a solid defense strategy. Each case is unique, and discussing the possible options with an attorney experienced in representing those charged with DUIs can help those accused begin to move forward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Source:&lt;/b&gt; dmv.org, &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dmv.org/ct-connecticut/automotive-law/dui.php&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;DUI &amp;amp; DWI in Connecticut&lt;/a&gt;&quot; Sep. 03, 2014&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2014 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.paolettilaw.net//drunk-driving/2014/09/03/drunk-driving-possible-penalties.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.paolettilaw.net//drunk-driving/2014/09/03/drunk-driving-possible-penalties.html</guid>
        
        <category>ignition interlock device</category>
        
        <category>legal limit</category>
        
        <category>license suspension</category>
        
        <category>penalties</category>
        
        
        <category>drunk-driving</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Domestic violence: Does there have to be physical proof?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;While physical evidence such as photographs of bruising can certainly result in domestic violence charges, physical proof of an alleged altercation does not have to be present for an individual to be charged with domestic violence in Connecticut. If physical documentation does exist, however, it can have serious implications for the defendants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/Domestic-Violence/&quot;&gt;Domestic violence&lt;/a&gt; charges commonly result from accusations of physical violence, but they can also be pressed if there are allegations of sexual, emotional or psychological abuse. Emotional and psychological abuse obviously are impossible to show with any kind of physical evidence, which is why they are often the hardest to prove and easiest to defend against. Many of these cases don't even make it to court because it is too difficult to show that the alleged abuse is severe enough to warrant criminal charges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When a person is accused of physically or sexually assaulting a spouse, partner or other family member, there may be documentation such as pictures taken by police, but this is not always true. It is well known that alleged domestic violence situations do not always involve a cooperative other party, and sometimes accusations do not come out until after any physical evidence that might have been there is gone. In some cases, domestic violence charges may be filed without physical proof if there are witness statements that corroborate the accusations or if there are medical records that suggest suspicious injuries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Domestic violence charges should also be taken seriously, even if the defendant is falsely accused. A conviction of this type can keep a person from working in certain industries and can impact any ongoing divorce or child custody situations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Source:&lt;/b&gt; FindLaw, &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http://family.findlaw.com/domestic-violence/types-of-domestic-violence.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Types of Domestic Violence&lt;/a&gt;&quot; Aug. 25, 2014&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 29 Aug 2014 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.paolettilaw.net//domestic-violence/2014/08/29/domestic-violence-does-there-have-to-be-physical-proof.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.paolettilaw.net//domestic-violence/2014/08/29/domestic-violence-does-there-have-to-be-physical-proof.html</guid>
        
        <category>allegations</category>
        
        <category>criminal charges</category>
        
        <category>domestic violence charges</category>
        
        
        <category>domestic-violence</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Murder conviction overturned, case could be headed back to trial</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A Connecticut man who had previously sentenced to 60 years in prison after being found guilty of murder has now succeeded in getting the conviction overturned and may be headed for a new trial. According to reports, the man was convicted of &lt;a href=&quot;/Violent-Crimes/&quot;&gt;murder&lt;/a&gt; in 2011 after he was accused of fatally shooting another man outside of the Cardinal's Club on April 27, 2008.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The now 26-year-old man has been serving time in the Cheshire Correctional Institution. In the appeal, his attorney argued that the court did not allow the defense to thoroughly cross-examine the police officers who testified during the trial, and the Appellate Court found that the original judge sustained several of the prosecution's objections during the officers' cross-examinations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The case will not go directly to trial, as now that the conviction has been overturned, the state must decide whether or not it will request the Appellate Court's ruling to be certified. If that happens, the case could go all the way to the Supreme Court. If the certifications request is not put in or the Supreme Court declines the case, it would then move forward to trial.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This case provides an example of how the appeals process can be used successfully. The defense has the right to cross-examine witnesses in court as part of its strategy, and when the judicial process does not work as it should, it is important for defendants to understand their options after a conviction and have legal representation that can and will appeal the ruling if necessary. A new trial does not necessarily guarantee a different outcome, but it can give defendants another chance at a fair trial.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Source:&lt;/b&gt; New Haven Register, &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nhregister.com/general-news/20140811/connecticut-court-overturns-new-haven-mans-murder-conviction-orders-new-trial&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Connecticut court overturns New Haven man&amp;rsquo;s murder conviction, orders new trial&lt;/a&gt;&quot; Aug. 11, 2014&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2014 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.paolettilaw.net//violent-crimes/2014/08/22/murder-conviction-overturned-case-could-be-headed-back-to-trial.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.paolettilaw.net//violent-crimes/2014/08/22/murder-conviction-overturned-case-could-be-headed-back-to-trial.html</guid>
        
        <category>Violent Crimes</category>
        
        
        <category>violent-crimes</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Connecticut police officer accused of stomping on suspect</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A police officer in Connecticut has been arrested and charged for allegedly stomping on a man's head after the man was already on the ground. The man had been shot with a taser before he was stomped on. The charges say that this alleged attack was a violation of that man's rights, and a video of the incident has now surfaced.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The officer who was arrested was a part of the Bridgeport Police Department. He had been working with that department for more than a decade.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The attack in question happened back in 2011, though the man has just now been indicted. If he ends up being convicted of the charges, he could be put in jail for as long as 10 years. On top of that, he could have to pay a fine of as much as $250,000.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apparently, the whole incident began when two officers started chasing a suspect. They believed that he had a firearm. The suspect was in a van, but he jumped out of it and started running from the officers on foot. He ran into a park, and the officers used a taser to stop him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, while it appears in the video that both of those officers were kicking the downed man., the officer who was arrested did not even show up until he was already down. He drove up in his squad car, got out and stomped on the man.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyone who is facing &lt;a href=&quot;/Criminal-Defense/&quot;&gt;criminal charges&lt;/a&gt;, no matter what they are accused of having done, has a right to a fair trial. This is a legal right extended to all who are accused of crimes, whether they are civilians or members of the police force.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;b&gt;Source:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/b&gt;Huffington Post, &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2014/08/09/clive-higgins-charged-cop-stomping-suspects-head_n_5662829.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Clive Higgins, Cop, Charged For Allegedly Stomping On Suspect&amp;#039;s Head (GRAPHIC VIDEO)&lt;/a&gt;&quot; Aug. 08, 2014 &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2014 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.paolettilaw.net//criminal-defense/2014/08/15/connecticut-police-officer-accused-of-stomping-on-suspect.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.paolettilaw.net//criminal-defense/2014/08/15/connecticut-police-officer-accused-of-stomping-on-suspect.html</guid>
        
        <category>criminal charge</category>
        
        
        <category>criminal-defense</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Two arrested on drug charges at Connecticut motel</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Two Connecticut residents are facing drug charges after police arrested them at a motel in Manchester. According to reports, police had the Studio 6 Motel under surveillance when they were told that a man and prostitute were reportedly meeting in one of the hotel's rooms. Officers say they watched as the 44-year-old man knocked on the door of the room and threw what they later identified as heroin into a garbage can.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Police reported that they then approached the 44-year-old's car, where a 30-year-old woman was sitting in the driver's seat. The woman was allegedly rolling a marijuana blunt when officers approached. Police searched the car and reported finding nine grams of marijuana with an approximate value of $100, 16 grams of cocaine worth a reported $600, $500 worth of heroin divided into 96 packets, multiple cellphones and cash in excess of $1,000.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The two were arrested, and both are facing charges of &lt;a href=&quot;/Drug-Charges/&quot;&gt;possession&lt;/a&gt; of drugs in a school zone, possession with intent to sell and possession of heroin, cocaine and marijuana. Bond was set at $100,000 for each of them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In any situation where there are allegations of drug possession, the search and seizure procedure is of great interest to the defense. If officers do not follow the proper protocols or have probable cause for the search, it may be possible in some cases to have the evidence ruled inadmissible in court. For defendants wanting to learn more about the charges against them and their options, talking with someone experienced with the way that drug cases are processed through the courts can be a first step.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;b&gt;Source:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/b&gt;WVIT, &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nbcconnecticut.com/news/local/Cops-Sniff-Out-Drugs-During-Prostitution-Bust-at-Manchester-Motel-269140331.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Police Make Drug Bust at Manchester Motel&lt;/a&gt;&quot; Jul. 29, 2014 &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 08 Aug 2014 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.paolettilaw.net//drug-charges/2014/08/08/two-arrested-on-drug-charges-at-connecticut-motel.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.paolettilaw.net//drug-charges/2014/08/08/two-arrested-on-drug-charges-at-connecticut-motel.html</guid>
        
        <category>Drug charges</category>
        
        <category>arrest</category>
        
        <category>defense</category>
        
        <category>drug possession</category>
        
        <category>search and seizure</category>
        
        
        <category>drug-charges</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Man facing DUI after picking up son from police</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A Connecticut man has been charged with drunk driving after he allegedly exhibited signs of intoxication when he went to pick up his son. According to reports, the Oxford man's 15-year-old son had been detained at the Naugatuck State Forest by officers after he allegedly had been caught riding a motor scooter illegally. The teen's three friends were also detained, according to the Department of Energy and Environmental Protection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officers had initially come to the scene after reports of people swimming in the reservoir. One of the 15-year-old's friends was apparently among the swimmers. Officers issued the teen a warning. Authorities say that the four teenagers were riding the gas-powered vehicles on town roads and in the forest on July 16. Connecticut state law requires that motor scooter riders must be 16 years of age or older and have the proper licenses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officers with DEEP reportedly called the 39-year-old man to come and pick up his son. However, when he arrived, officers believed he had been drinking and gave him a field sobriety test. Police claim the man failed both the field sobriety test and a subsequent Breathalyzer test. He was arrested and charged with &lt;a href=&quot;/DUI-DWI/&quot;&gt;driving under the influence&lt;/a&gt; and was released after posting a $500 bond. The next court date was scheduled for July 25.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Driving while drinking is never a good idea, even when there are extenuating circumstances. However, everyone has lapses in judgment. To move forward from these types of events, it is important that defendants understand how alternative defense options, such as a plea bargain or challenging the results of a field sobriety test, may be applicable in certain cases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;b&gt;Source:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/b&gt;NBC Connecticut, &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nbcconnecticut.com/news/local/Dad-Charged-With-Drunk-Driving-After-Picking-Up-Son-Who-Drove-Motor-Scooter-Illegally-DEEP-267537321.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Dad Charged With DUI While Picking Up Son Who Drove Scooter Illegally: DEEP&lt;/a&gt;&quot; Ari Mason, Jul. 17, 2014 &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2014 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.paolettilaw.net//drunk-driving/2014/08/01/man-facing-dui-after-picking-up-son-from-police.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.paolettilaw.net//drunk-driving/2014/08/01/man-facing-dui-after-picking-up-son-from-police.html</guid>
        
        <category>field sobriety test</category>
        
        
        <category>drunk-driving</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Signing of Connecticut bill means ignition interlocks even for first DUI</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em itemprop=&quot;description&quot;&gt;Starting next year, ignition interlocks will be required for all drunk driving offenders.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An ignition interlock is a small device that is wired into a vehicle's ignition system. The driver must blow into the device before starting the vehicle. If the ignition interlock detects a certain measurable amount of alcohol, the vehicle will not start.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Connecticut, installation of an ignition interlock device has already been required for some drivers convicted of driving under the influence of alcohol. However, under a new bill recently signed by Governor Dannel Malloy, an ignition interlock will be required even for a
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.paolettilaw.net/DUI-DWI/First-Offenses.shtml&quot;&gt;first DUI offense&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Ignition interlocks can be inconvenient and expensive&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Specifically, the new law authorizes the Department of Motor Vehicles to take administrative action in requiring ignition interlock installation for first-time DUI offenders. While the law does reduce the mandatory license suspension period for some drunk driving violations, it will impose ignition interlock requirements at the conclusion of license suspensions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the past, mandatory ignition interlocks were reserved in Connecticut for those believed to present a particular danger to other motorists. Now however, ignition interlocks will be required for DUI convictions and Department of Motor Vehicle Administrative Per Se Suspensions even if it is the offender's first time being in trouble with the legal system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having to use an ignition interlock can obviously be embarrassing and inconvenient. But it can also be cripplingly expensive. Just to participate in Connecticut's ignition interlock program, you must pay a series of hefty fees to the Department of Motor Vehicles. Once your fees have been paid and your application approved, you must pay an ignition interlock vendor to install a device. After the ignition interlock is installed, you are responsible for maintenance costs and service fees from the vendor. Eventually, you will have to pay to have the ignition interlock removed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new ignition interlock bill was signed into law on August 11 in a ceremony held on the front plaza of the Fairfield Police Department headquarters. The law goes into effect on July 1, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Get help from a DUI defense attorney if you are facing charges&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are being accused of driving under the influence of alcohol in Connecticut, you are facing some harsh consequences, the potential for mandatory installation of an ignition interlock being just one of them. However, you do have legal rights, and by staging a strong legal defense, you may be able to avoid some of the worst consequences of a DUI conviction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Protect your future and your freedom. Talk to a Connecticut DUI defense lawyer today if you are being accused of drunk driving.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Keywords: &amp;lt;span itemprop=&quot;keywords&quot;&amp;gt;ignition interlock, drunk driving, Connecticut&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.paolettilaw.net//articles/2014/01/12/Signing-of-Connecticut-bill-means-ignition-interlocks-even-for-first-DUI.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.paolettilaw.net//articles/2014/01/12/Signing-of-Connecticut-bill-means-ignition-interlocks-even-for-first-DUI.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>articles</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Warrant required for police cellphone searches, Court rules</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Police are now required to obtain a warrant before searching the cellphone of a person who has been placed under arrest, according to the United States Supreme Court. With certain limited exceptions, the Court's recent ruling establishes that warrantless cellphone searches by police are unconstitutional.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Fourth Amendment to the United States Constitution prohibits police from conducting unreasonable searches and seizures. The exact meaning of &amp;quot;unreasonable,&amp;quot; however, depends on the circumstances.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Search incident to arrest&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When a person is lawfully &lt;a href=&quot;/Criminal-Defense/What-to-Do-if-You-Are-Arrested.shtml&quot;&gt;arrested&lt;/a&gt; - meaning that the arrest is supported by probable cause - police generally do not need a warrant to conduct an initial search of the suspect's vehicle or personal belongings, such as a backpack, purse or briefcase.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This type of search, known as a search incident to arrest, allows officers to search for concealed weapons or other evidence of criminal activity that may be within the suspect's reach. It is thought to be reasonable because it helps protect officers' safety and prevent the destruction of evidence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Home searches&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In contrast, police are usually required to obtain a warrant before they can conduct a search of a person's home. This is because there is thought to be a higher expectation of privacy within the home than in a vehicle or in public.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thus, a police search of the home is thought to be more invasive and therefore requires a greater degree of justification to be considered reasonable. Except in emergencies and certain other limited circumstances, a police search of the home without a warrant is considered unreasonable and is therefore barred by the Fourth Amendment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Court says cellphone searches are highly invasive&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The central issue in the recent case was whether cellphone searches should be treated more like searches incident to arrest or home searches. The Court ruled unanimously for the latter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More than 90 percent of adults in the United States own cellphones, the Court reasoned in its written opinion, and these devices often contain digital records of nearly every aspect of the owner's life. Using the information contained on or accessible through a person's cellphone, such as emails, photographs, internet search records and other data, it is possible to reconstruct the owner's personal life in great detail. Thus, the Court concluded, cellphones deserve a higher degree of protection from police searches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Evidence obtained from illegal searches may be barred&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When police violate a person's constitutional rights by conducting an unlawful search, it is sometimes possible to stop any evidence discovered during that search from being used in court. If you have been arrested for a crime, be sure to talk to a lawyer to learn more about your rights and the options that are available to help protect your interests.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.paolettilaw.net//articles/2014/01/11/Warrant-required-for-police-cellphone-searches-Court-rules.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.paolettilaw.net//articles/2014/01/11/Warrant-required-for-police-cellphone-searches-Court-rules.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>articles</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
