<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<style>

<?xml-stylesheet href="/includes/blog-feed/atom.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Your awesome title</title>
    <description>Write an awesome description for your new site here. You can edit this line in _config.yml. It will appear in your document head meta (for Google search results) and in your feed.xml site description.
</description>
    <link>http://yourdomain.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://yourdomain.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2015 19:42:56 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2015 19:42:56 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.5.3</generator>
    
      <entry>
        <title>Criminal defense in Connecticut</title>
        <description>Even innocent people can get in trouble with the law and get accused of a criminal act. This is why our legal system puts the burden of proof on the prosecution during a criminal case. Indeed, if the prosecution cannot prove that the accused person is guilty of his or her criminal charges beyond a reasonable doubt, then the person will not be found guilty or punished for the alleged crime.</description>
        <published>Fri, 23 Jan 2015 00:00:00 -0500</published>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/criminal%20defense/2015/01/23/criminal-defense-in-connecticut.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/criminal%20defense/2015/01/23/criminal-defense-in-connecticut.html</guid>
        
        <category>criminal defense</category>
        
      </entry>
    
      <entry>
        <title>Does domestic violence affect firearm ownership?</title>
        <description>Accusations of domestic violence often stem from stories of abuse in a relationship. Many cases of domestic violence involve a spouse abusing the other spouse or a romantic partner abusing the other romantic partner. Children and other cohabitants and family members may also become the victims of domestic violence.</description>
        <published>Fri, 16 Jan 2015 00:00:00 -0500</published>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/domestic%20violence/2015/01/16/does-domestic-violence-affect-firearm-ownership.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/domestic%20violence/2015/01/16/does-domestic-violence-affect-firearm-ownership.html</guid>
        
        <category>domestic violence</category>
        
      </entry>
    
      <entry>
        <title>Could overdose kits help stop heroin deaths in Connecticut?</title>
        <description>Every year, numerous people die from heroin overdoses in the United States and Connecticut. The traditional approach of increasing punishments associated with heroin crimes is the way lawmakers tend to combat the problem. However, lawmakers in one southeast state are trying a new strategy.</description>
        <published>Thu, 08 Jan 2015 00:00:00 -0500</published>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/drug%20charges/2015/01/08/could-overdose-kits-help-stop-heroin-deaths-in-connecticut.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/drug%20charges/2015/01/08/could-overdose-kits-help-stop-heroin-deaths-in-connecticut.html</guid>
        
        <category>drug charges</category>
        
      </entry>
    
      <entry>
        <title>A new type of impaired driving in Connecticut</title>
        <description>Did you know that last December was National Impaired Driving Prevention Month? President Obama gave the month this title to help raise awareness for the dangers of being impaired in any way while behind the wheel. Many people think of drugs and alcohol when they think of impaired driving, but it is important to remember that distracted driving can be dangerous as well.</description>
        <published>Fri, 02 Jan 2015 00:00:00 -0500</published>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/drunk%20driving/2015/01/02/a-new-type-of-impaired-driving-in-connecticut.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/drunk%20driving/2015/01/02/a-new-type-of-impaired-driving-in-connecticut.html</guid>
        
        <category>drunk driving</category>
        
      </entry>
    
      <entry>
        <title>Were you charged with domestic violence over the holidays?</title>
        <description>Did you know that the holidays are a time when numerous domestic violence complaints take place? The problem is that relatives who have not seen each other in some time tend to get together during Christmas and over New Year&#39;s Eve and this -- in some families -- can be a recipe for disaster.</description>
        <published>Fri, 26 Dec 2014 00:00:00 -0500</published>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/domestic%20violence/2014/12/26/were-you-charged-with-domestic-violence-over-the-holidays.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/domestic%20violence/2014/12/26/were-you-charged-with-domestic-violence-over-the-holidays.html</guid>
        
        <category>domestic violence</category>
        
      </entry>
    
      <entry>
        <title>What are the laws governing drunk driving in Connecticut?</title>
        <description>If you have been arrested and face a DUI charge in Connecticut, you will want to know what kinds of rules and regulations apply to you and your case. By familiarizing yourself with the law, you can figure out where you stand in your case, and you can better avoid more DUI charges in the future.</description>
        <published>Thu, 18 Dec 2014 00:00:00 -0500</published>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/drunk%20driving/2014/12/18/what-are-the-laws-governing-drunk-driving-in-connecticut.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/drunk%20driving/2014/12/18/what-are-the-laws-governing-drunk-driving-in-connecticut.html</guid>
        
        <category>drunk driving</category>
        
      </entry>
    
      <entry>
        <title>Criminal defense against parole violation charges</title>
        <description>Unfortunately, the criminal defense of individuals accused of crimes in Connecticut does not always end with the conclusion of their criminal case. If a criminal conviction results in jail time and a subsequent parole sentence, for example, the accused person might inadvertently violate his or her parole or be accused of violating parole. In such cases, the person will then need to defend against the parole violation charge.</description>
        <published>Thu, 11 Dec 2014 00:00:00 -0500</published>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/criminal%20defense/2014/12/11/criminal-defense-against-parole-violation-charges.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/criminal%20defense/2014/12/11/criminal-defense-against-parole-violation-charges.html</guid>
        
        <category>criminal defense</category>
        
      </entry>
    
      <entry>
        <title>Drunk driving and DUI checkpoints in Connecticut</title>
        <description>With the exception of some states, most states -- including Connecticut -- allow for DUI checkpoints. DUI checkpoints are usually more prevalent around major holidays, when it is more common for motor vehicle operators to drive home drunk from a party. The checkpoints are often set up at intersections, and officers will stop vehicles randomly to check for indications that the drivers are drunk.</description>
        <published>Thu, 04 Dec 2014 00:00:00 -0500</published>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/drunk%20driving/2014/12/04/drunk-driving-and-dui-checkpoints-in-connecticut.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/drunk%20driving/2014/12/04/drunk-driving-and-dui-checkpoints-in-connecticut.html</guid>
        
        <category>drunk driving</category>
        
      </entry>
    
      <entry>
        <title>Driver from out-of-state faces reckless driving and DUI charge</title>
        <description>Drunk driving allegations are serious, but sometimes they are not the only thing that a driver gets accused of during a traffic stop. Indeed, a DUI charge might be combined with a speeding citation, a reckless driving violation or -- in more grave cases where a fatal traffic accident is involved -- manslaughter. For this reason, a DUI defense is not always just about drunk driving. Sometimes, individuals have to defend themselves against other charges too.</description>
        <published>Fri, 28 Nov 2014 00:00:00 -0500</published>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/drunk%20driving/2014/11/28/driver-from-out-of-state-faces-reckless-driving-and-dui-charge.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/drunk%20driving/2014/11/28/driver-from-out-of-state-faces-reckless-driving-and-dui-charge.html</guid>
        
        <category>drunk driving</category>
        
      </entry>
    
      <entry>
        <title>Drug charges: Challenging evidence</title>
        <description>In any criminal case involving allegations of drug possession or distribution, how the evidence was obtained is of primary importance. Any drugs, paraphernalia or other materials must be seized legally to be used as evidence in a trial. While many defendants assume that the search warrants involved were obtained with probable cause and executed properly, this is not always the case.</description>
        <published>Thu, 20 Nov 2014 00:00:00 -0500</published>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/drug%20charges/2014/11/20/drug-charges-challenging-evidence.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/drug%20charges/2014/11/20/drug-charges-challenging-evidence.html</guid>
        
        <category>drug charges</category>
        
      </entry>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
